[
  {
    "questionNum": 70001,
    "questionText": " Prices and Production was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Friedrich Hayek"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70002,
    "questionText": " Largest Dome (World)?",
    "answerText": " 'Astrodome' in Housten; Texas (USA) outside diameter 216 metres and inside 196 metres."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70003,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Memories and Musings”?",
    "answerText": " K.P.S.Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70004,
    "questionText": " The science dealing with the study of the heart and its diseases is known as?",
    "answerText": " Cardiology."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70005,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Warof Indian Independence ?",
    "answerText": " V.D.Sarvarkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70006,
    "questionText": " Phytopathology is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Plant diseases"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70007,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of One Hundred Years of Solitude?",
    "answerText": " Gabriel Garcia Marquez"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70008,
    "questionText": " I.F.A. Shield is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football (Calcutta)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70009,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Law Verses Justice?",
    "answerText": " V.R. Krishna Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70010,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Past and Present”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Carlyle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70011,
    "questionText": " Which was the last ruling dynasty of China?",
    "answerText": " Ching dynasty or the Manchus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70012,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Thieves in the Night”?",
    "answerText": " Arthur Koestler"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70013,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Freedom at Midnight ?",
    "answerText": " Larry Collins and Dominique Lapierre"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70014,
    "questionText": " Who is the father of Indian Green Revolution ?",
    "answerText": " M.S. Swaminathan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70015,
    "questionText": " Whis is the Smallest seeds?",
    "answerText": " Orchid seeds"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70016,
    "questionText": " The Eravikulam was declared as a NationalPark in?",
    "answerText": 1978
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70017,
    "questionText": " The year in whichTelegraph system started in Travancore is?",
    "answerText": 1863
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70018,
    "questionText": " Who was the immediate successor of prophet Muhammed or first Khalifa?",
    "answerText": " Abubekker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70019,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Facts and Facts”?",
    "answerText": " Khan Abdul WaliKhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70020,
    "questionText": " Which missionary is the author of Samkshepa Vedartham (1772)?",
    "answerText": " Clement Pianos"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70021,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Hindu View of Life?",
    "answerText": " Dr Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70022,
    "questionText": " Which king of England was dethroned through the Bloodless Revolution ?",
    "answerText": " James II"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70023,
    "questionText": " Musiris is the old name of?",
    "answerText": " Kodungallur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70024,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Burial at Sea”?",
    "answerText": " Khushwant Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70025,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Namesake”?",
    "answerText": " Jumpa Lahiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70026,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Faces of Everest”?",
    "answerText": " Maj H P SAhluwalia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70027,
    "questionText": " Agricultural University with its headquarters at Mannuthi in Thrissur was founded in?",
    "answerText": 1971
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70028,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Olympian of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " C K Lakshman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70029,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Printing Press?",
    "answerText": " Caxton"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70030,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Tuberculosis bacilli?",
    "answerText": " Robert Koch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70031,
    "questionText": " Father of DNA Finger Printing ?",
    "answerText": " Prof.Alec Jeffreys"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70032,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “‘Life and Times’”?",
    "answerText": " V.V.Giri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70033,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of I too Had a Dream ?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Varghese Kurian"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70034,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Indian Philosophy;?",
    "answerText": " Dr. S.Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70035,
    "questionText": " Palynology is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Pollen and spores"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70036,
    "questionText": " The Opium wars were fought between ?",
    "answerText": " Britain and China"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70037,
    "questionText": " Which is the official publication of Kerala Bhasha Institute?",
    "answerText": " Vijnana Kairali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70038,
    "questionText": " Father of Cytology?",
    "answerText": " Robert Hook"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70039,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Castle?",
    "answerText": " Franz Kafka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70040,
    "questionText": " Programme 150 is the first Robert developed by ?",
    "answerText": " C-DAC"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70041,
    "questionText": " Land of Thousand Elephants?",
    "answerText": " Laos"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70042,
    "questionText": " Theory of Games and Economic Behavior was written by ?",
    "answerText": " John Von Neumann and Oskar Morgenstern"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70043,
    "questionText": " Indian Toxicology Research Centre is located at?",
    "answerText": " Lucknow (Uttar Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70044,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Computer (electronic)?",
    "answerText": " J . G . Brainerd J.P.Eckert & J.W.Manchly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70045,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Pracheena Malayalam’?",
    "answerText": " Chatampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70046,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Socialistic Evening”?",
    "answerText": " Shobha De"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70047,
    "questionText": " Largest ape is ?",
    "answerText": " Gorilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70048,
    "questionText": " First Indian Woman to win an Olympic Medal?",
    "answerText": " Karnam Malleswari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70049,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The cat and Shakesphere”?",
    "answerText": " Raja Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70050,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Surgakanthi”?",
    "answerText": " G. Sankara Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70051,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Story of My Experiments with Truth”?",
    "answerText": " Gandhiji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70052,
    "questionText": " Central Sanskrit Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Tirupati (Andhra Pradesh)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70053,
    "questionText": " CT Scanning (Computed Tomographic Scanning) - Developed by ?",
    "answerText": " Godfrey Hounsfield in 1968(Nobel Prize in 1979)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70054,
    "questionText": " Walker Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Golf (England)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70055,
    "questionText": " Central Electro - Chemical Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Karaikudi (Tamil Nadu)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70056,
    "questionText": " Panniyar hydroelectric project is located in?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70057,
    "questionText": " Which is an eye ailment that causes increased pressure within the eye ball?",
    "answerText": " Glaucoma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70058,
    "questionText": " Which is the birth place of Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " Chempazhanthi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70059,
    "questionText": " National Institute of Oceanography is located at?",
    "answerText": " Panaji (Goa)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70060,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ The Village “?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70061,
    "questionText": " In which year the second Indo-Pak war was fought?",
    "answerText": 1971
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70062,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mending Wall”?",
    "answerText": " Robert Frost"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70063,
    "questionText": " Blood Pressure control is the function of which hormone?",
    "answerText": " Adrenalin produced by Adrenal gland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70064,
    "questionText": " Human Action was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Ludwig von Mises"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70065,
    "questionText": " Seismic Research Centre is located at?",
    "answerText": " Gaurividanur near Bangalore (Karnataka)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70066,
    "questionText": " Arjunanritham is a popular dance form in?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha and Kottayam Districts"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70067,
    "questionText": " Pandharpur is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Bhima"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70068,
    "questionText": " Which place is known as 'Southern Gaya'?",
    "answerText": " Thirunelveli in Wynad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70069,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Starry Nights”?",
    "answerText": " Shobha De"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70070,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ivan Hoe”?",
    "answerText": " Walter Scott"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70071,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “N issar Ahammed”",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammed Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70072,
    "questionText": " Land of Rising Sun?",
    "answerText": " Japan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70073,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Burkina faso?",
    "answerText": " Ouagadougou"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70074,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of My Country My Life?",
    "answerText": " LK.Advani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70075,
    "questionText": " Remedy for Astigmatism is to use ?",
    "answerText": " Cylindrical lens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70076,
    "questionText": " Kollam Era was started by?",
    "answerText": " Rajashekhara 'Varman Kulasekhara."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70077,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mayilpeeli”?",
    "answerText": " O.N.V Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70078,
    "questionText": " Famous Orator of Greece?",
    "answerText": " Cesero"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70079,
    "questionText": " The life span of RBC is about ?",
    "answerText": " 120 Days."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70080,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Jungle Book”?",
    "answerText": " Rudyard Kipling"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70081,
    "questionText": " The Theory of Free Banking was written by ?",
    "answerText": " George Selgin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70082,
    "questionText": " Washington is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Potomac"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70083,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Scenes from a writer's life”?",
    "answerText": " Ruskin Bond"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70084,
    "questionText": " The first Grama Panchayat which produced and distributed electricity on their own?",
    "answerText": " Mangulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70085,
    "questionText": " Iliad tells the story of ?",
    "answerText": " Trojan War"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70086,
    "questionText": " Vamanapuram River originates from?",
    "answerText": " Chemunji Mottai of the Western Ghats"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70087,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “War of Indian Independence”?",
    "answerText": " Vir Savarkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70088,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Amsterdam?",
    "answerText": " Ian McEwan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70089,
    "questionText": " DPEP is founded with the assistance of?",
    "answerText": " The World Bank"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70090,
    "questionText": " Tess",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70091,
    "questionText": " Ranji Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " National Cricket Championship"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70092,
    "questionText": " Battle of Water Loo (1815) British force led by Duke of Wellington defeated French force led by ?",
    "answerText": " Napolean Bonaparte"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70093,
    "questionText": " Who was the contemporary of Velu Thampi Dalawa who revolted against the British in Cochin?",
    "answerText": " Paliyat Achan; Diwan of Cochin Raja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70094,
    "questionText": " Coldest Desert?",
    "answerText": " Antarctica"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70095,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Adventures of Angle March”?",
    "answerText": " Saul Bellow"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70096,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Photography?",
    "answerText": " L.Daguerre"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70097,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Rayon?",
    "answerText": " Joseph Swann"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70098,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Christian?",
    "answerText": " John Bunyan."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70099,
    "questionText": " resulted in the Which treaty with English resulted in the loss of the political freedom of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " The treaty of 1805 by Velu Thampi Dalawa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70100,
    "questionText": " On which date Marthandavarma dedicated the kingdom to Sri. Padmanabaha of Trivandrum (Thrippatidanam) ?",
    "answerText": " Wednesday; January 3; 1750 (Makararn 5; 725 KE)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70101,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “A Hindu View of Life”?",
    "answerText": " Dr. S.Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70102,
    "questionText": " Land of Five Seas?",
    "answerText": " South West Asia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70103,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Lady with the Lamp?",
    "answerText": " Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70104,
    "questionText": " .........:... contain the list of the endangered species of plants and animals?",
    "answerText": " Red Data Books"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70105,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Kashmir- Behind the Vale?",
    "answerText": " MJ. Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70106,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Natural Selection; Laws of?",
    "answerText": " Darwin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70107,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Kuppuvachanm Kodachi”",
    "answerText": " OV.Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70108,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Cells in the plants?",
    "answerText": " Robert Hooke"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70109,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Rights of Man”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Paine"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70110,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “My Life and Times”?",
    "answerText": " V.V.Giri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70111,
    "questionText": " Who was the first President of Travancore State Congress?",
    "answerText": " Pattom Thanu Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70112,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Geometry?",
    "answerText": " Euclid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70113,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “View from Delhi; ”?",
    "answerText": " A Chester Bowles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70114,
    "questionText": " Theory of Population was stipulated by?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Malthus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70115,
    "questionText": " Agnisakshi is the work of?",
    "answerText": " Lalithambika Antharjanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70116,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Randamoozham”?",
    "answerText": " M.T.Vasudevan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70117,
    "questionText": " Who was the first to write the biography of Karl Marx in Malayalam?",
    "answerText": " Swadeshabhimani K. Ramakrishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70118,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Blood grouping?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Costella and Dr.Moss"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70119,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Malayali Novelist ?",
    "answerText": " Appu Nedungadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70120,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Book of Unforgettable Women”?",
    "answerText": " Khushwant Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70121,
    "questionText": " Plague; an insect borne disease; is propagated by?",
    "answerText": " Rat flea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70122,
    "questionText": " Malaria; an insect borne disease; is propagated by?",
    "answerText": " Anopheles female mosquito."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70123,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kargil - A Soldier's Diary”?",
    "answerText": " Harvinder Baweja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70124,
    "questionText": " Which civilization were credited for the invention of the system of dividing a circle into 360 degrees?",
    "answerText": " Assirians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70125,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Agony and the Ecstasy?",
    "answerText": " Arthur Halley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70126,
    "questionText": " The present term of French President is?",
    "answerText": " Five years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70127,
    "questionText": " The approximate number of bones in a new born baby is?",
    "answerText": " 300 bones"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70128,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Pinjar ?",
    "answerText": " Amrita Pritam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70129,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Indian Summers”?",
    "answerText": " John Wright"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70130,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tess of the D’Urbervilles”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70131,
    "questionText": " T.K. Madhavan; K. Kelappan; KP. Keshavamenon were the major-leaders of?",
    "answerText": " Vaikkam Sathyagraha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70132,
    "questionText": " First five centuries of the Christian Era are known as?",
    "answerText": " Sangham Age."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70133,
    "questionText": " First Democratic President of South Africa is ?",
    "answerText": " Nelson Mandela"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70134,
    "questionText": " Quaker City?",
    "answerText": " Philadelphia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70135,
    "questionText": " Sankaracharya was a Namboothiri Brahmin born at ?",
    "answerText": " Kaladi on the banks of river Periyar."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70136,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “‘The Three Musketeers’”?",
    "answerText": " Alexander Dumas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70137,
    "questionText": " PET Scan is Positron Emission Tomography scan is used for studying?",
    "answerText": " Brain"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70138,
    "questionText": " What is known as the power house of the cell?",
    "answerText": " Mitochondria"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70139,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Only one Year”?",
    "answerText": " Svetlana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70140,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Libya?",
    "answerText": " Libya Dinar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70141,
    "questionText": " National Sugar Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kanpur (U.P.)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70142,
    "questionText": " Longest Rail Tunnel?",
    "answerText": " Bombay-Pune route"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70143,
    "questionText": " The name 'Anchal' was given to the early postal system of Kerala by?",
    "answerText": " Col. Munro"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70144,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Conflict of Laws in India '?",
    "answerText": " V.C.Govindaraj"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70145,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Snows of Kilimanjaro”?",
    "answerText": " Earnest Hemingway."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70146,
    "questionText": " Which element helps in greening of plants and their rapid growth?",
    "answerText": " Nitrogen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70147,
    "questionText": " Karamana river (67 km) originates from?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70148,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Kadaltheerathu”?",
    "answerText": " O.V Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70149,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Far from the Madding Crowd ?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70150,
    "questionText": " Who is known as' Italian Kautilya?",
    "answerText": " Niccolo Machiavelli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70151,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Mexico?",
    "answerText": " Mexico City"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70152,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Adventures of Huckleberry Finn”?",
    "answerText": " Mark Twain (Samuel Clemens)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70153,
    "questionText": " To which community Kapilar and Paranar famous poets of Sangham Age; belonged to?",
    "answerText": " The 'Pana' community."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70154,
    "questionText": " What is the total number of Additional District Courts in Kerala?",
    "answerText": 29
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70155,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “India- The Critical years”?",
    "answerText": " Kuldip Nayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70156,
    "questionText": " The 'Bhadradeepam' and 'Murajapam' in the Padmanabha Swami Temple was started by?",
    "answerText": " Marthandavarma."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70157,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Eye of the Storm”?",
    "answerText": " Patrick White"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70158,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Sudan?",
    "answerText": " Sudanese Pound"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70159,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Russia?",
    "answerText": " Rouble"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70160,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Idiot ?",
    "answerText": " Fyodor Dostoyevsky"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70161,
    "questionText": " The Currency of British Honduras?",
    "answerText": " Dollar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70162,
    "questionText": " Name the disease caused by the bite of a mad dog?",
    "answerText": " Rabies or Hydrophobia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70163,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Sierra Leone?",
    "answerText": " Freetown"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70164,
    "questionText": " The Commonsense?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Paine"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70165,
    "questionText": " The first women's prison was established in 1996 at?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70166,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters “Dr. Watson; Sherlock Holmes”",
    "answerText": " Arthur Conan Doyle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70167,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Seven Lamps of Architecture”?",
    "answerText": " John Ruskin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70168,
    "questionText": " Vivekachudamani; Updeshasahasri; Atmabodha; Mohamudgara; Sivanandalahari and Saundarya lahari are the poems composed by?",
    "answerText": " Sankaracharya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70169,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Liberty and Death”?",
    "answerText": " Patrick French"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70170,
    "questionText": " ‘Vitruvian Man’ also called the Canon of Proportions is the world famous drawing by?",
    "answerText": " Leonardo da Vinchi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70171,
    "questionText": " The Chief Court became the High Court during the diwanship of?",
    "answerText": " Shanmukham Chettiyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70172,
    "questionText": " Institute of Microbial Technology is located at?",
    "answerText": " Hyderabad."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70173,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Air-brake?",
    "answerText": " G e o r g e Westinghouse"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70174,
    "questionText": " Which philospher was considered as a 'Walking University'?",
    "answerText": " Aristotle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70175,
    "questionText": " Blood sucking Leech possess anti coagulant called ?",
    "answerText": " Hirudin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70176,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Wonder That Was India ?",
    "answerText": " A L Basham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70177,
    "questionText": " The first systematic census of Travancore was taken on May 18; 1875 by?",
    "answerText": " AyilyamThirunal."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70178,
    "questionText": " Chin dynasty of China was founded by ?",
    "answerText": " Shih Hwangti"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70179,
    "questionText": " Highest Volcano (World)?",
    "answerText": " Cotopoxi (Andes; Eucador)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70180,
    "questionText": " James Bond",
    "answerText": " Ian Fleming"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70181,
    "questionText": " American stock exchange is situated in New York at?",
    "answerText": " Wall Street"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70182,
    "questionText": " Thirumukathu Pilla;",
    "answerText": " c.V.Ramanpilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70183,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Cashew is?",
    "answerText": " Anacardium Occidentale"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70184,
    "questionText": " The official name of Japan is ?",
    "answerText": " Nippon or Nihon; (means the source of the Sun)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70185,
    "questionText": " 'Uncle Tom's Cabin of Harriet Beechstowe was published for the first time in?",
    "answerText": 1852
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70186,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Israel?",
    "answerText": " New Shekel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70187,
    "questionText": " Ancient religion of Japan?",
    "answerText": " Shintoism"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70188,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “For Whom the Bell Tolls”?",
    "answerText": " Ernest Hemingway"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70189,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Childhood?",
    "answerText": " Maxim Gorky"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70190,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Dream of Fair to Middling women”?",
    "answerText": " Samuel Beckett"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70191,
    "questionText": " Who were the Chief Ministers of Dharmaraja?",
    "answerText": " Ayyappan Marthanda Pillai and Raja kesava Das"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70192,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tsunami - 7 Hours that Shook the World”?",
    "answerText": " Satinder Blndra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70193,
    "questionText": " Who appointed Veluthampi as his commerce minister and then the Dalawa of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Balarama Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70194,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ A Suitable Boy”?",
    "answerText": " Vikram Seth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70195,
    "questionText": " Largest physical and chemical molecules for cell are?",
    "answerText": " Proteins"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70196,
    "questionText": " Vittal Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70197,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Peacock is?",
    "answerText": " Pavo cristatus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70198,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Duravastha”?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70199,
    "questionText": " Christianity reached England for the first time by the coming of?",
    "answerText": " Romans"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70200,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Divine Life ?",
    "answerText": " Swami Sivananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70201,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of 'Ardhanareeswara Sthothram' ?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70202,
    "questionText": " Garden City?",
    "answerText": " Chicago"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70203,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Nalukettu “?",
    "answerText": " M.T.Vasudevan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70204,
    "questionText": " HIV is a ?",
    "answerText": " RNA virus."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70205,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Gambia?",
    "answerText": " Banjul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70206,
    "questionText": " The Capital of U.S.A.?",
    "answerText": " Washington D.C."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70207,
    "questionText": " The term' Biology' is coined by which French naturalist?",
    "answerText": " Jean Lamarck."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70208,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “A Farewall to Arms”?",
    "answerText": " Earnest Hemingway"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70209,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Azuravithu “?",
    "answerText": " M.T.Vasudevan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70210,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Malaysia?",
    "answerText": " Kuala Lumpur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70211,
    "questionText": " Peoples Republic of China' was formed in the year?",
    "answerText": 1949
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70212,
    "questionText": " Punnapra Vayalar Rebellion was in ?",
    "answerText": 1946
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70213,
    "questionText": " Where was the first Radio Station in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70214,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Birth and Death of the Sun?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70215,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Rakthapushpangal”?",
    "answerText": " Changampuzha Krishna Pilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70216,
    "questionText": " Normal pulse rate of healthy adult human is ?",
    "answerText": " 72 per minute."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70217,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Durgesh Nan-dini?",
    "answerText": " Bankim Chandra Chatterjee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70218,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters Appunni; Amarsingh;?",
    "answerText": " M.T. Vasudevan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70219,
    "questionText": " What is the civil wars in England called?",
    "answerText": " Battle of Roses"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70220,
    "questionText": " Forest HIlls (New York) is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Tennis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70221,
    "questionText": " What was the name of the ship in which Vasco-da-Gama reached Kerala?",
    "answerText": " St.Gabriel."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70222,
    "questionText": " Wrinkles in old age are due to deficiency of ?",
    "answerText": " Collagen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70223,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Ganapati”?",
    "answerText": " Vallathol Narayana Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70224,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Man for All Seasons?",
    "answerText": " Robert Bolt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70225,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Gods Little Soldier ?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Nagarkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70226,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Kore Kagaz ?",
    "answerText": " Amrita Pritam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70227,
    "questionText": " First India’s Spaceman?",
    "answerText": " Sqn. Ldr. Rakesh Sharma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70228,
    "questionText": " Trent Bridge (England) is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70229,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Ambassador's Report ?",
    "answerText": " Chester Bowles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70230,
    "questionText": " Dance form in Argentina is known as ?",
    "answerText": " Tango"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70231,
    "questionText": " Aeneid was written by?",
    "answerText": " Virgil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70232,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ordeal to Love”?",
    "answerText": " Huge Tinker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70233,
    "questionText": " Friday; Robinson Crusoe",
    "answerText": " Daniel Defoe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70234,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Norway?",
    "answerText": " Oslo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70235,
    "questionText": " The name Japan was originated from the name Zipangu. By whom was this name coined ?",
    "answerText": " Marco Polo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70236,
    "questionText": " was the first woman judge of India?",
    "answerText": " Justice Anna Chandy -1937"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70237,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Antony and Cleopatra ?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70238,
    "questionText": " Sethu Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Aquatics"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70239,
    "questionText": " In which year the first Indo-Pak war was fought?",
    "answerText": 1965
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70240,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Pamela”?",
    "answerText": " Samuel Richardson."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70241,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Meghdoot”?",
    "answerText": " Kalidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70242,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Electric Motor (AC)?",
    "answerText": " Nikola Tesla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70243,
    "questionText": " The Punnapra Vayalar Upheaval was a strike against?",
    "answerText": " The American Model irremovable executive."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70244,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Reminiscences of Nehru Age”?",
    "answerText": " M.O.Mathai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70245,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Saz-i- Watan ?",
    "answerText": " Munshi Prem Chand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70246,
    "questionText": " The Republic of China was formed in ?",
    "answerText": 1912
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70247,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Silent Woman”?",
    "answerText": " Ben Johnson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70248,
    "questionText": " Pakistan observes its independence day on ?",
    "answerText": " 14-Aug-17"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70249,
    "questionText": " The district with least number of post offices in Kerala is?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70250,
    "questionText": " The Tianen Square in Beijing is described as ?",
    "answerText": " 'Naval of China' (means 'the gate of heavenly peace')"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70251,
    "questionText": " Central Road Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " New Delhi (Delhi)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70252,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Origin of Life (artificial)?",
    "answerText": " Stanley Millar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70253,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Sao Tome and Principle?",
    "answerText": " Sao Tome"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70254,
    "questionText": " World's first heart transplantation was performed on 3rd December 1967 by?",
    "answerText": " Christian Bernard."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70255,
    "questionText": " Longest Dam (India)?",
    "answerText": " Hirakud Dam on the river Mahanadi -Orissa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70256,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Friends and Foes”?",
    "answerText": " Sheikh Mujibur Rehman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70257,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Human Knowledge”?",
    "answerText": " Bertrand Russell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70258,
    "questionText": " Plague causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Yersinia pestis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70259,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Death in Venice”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Mann"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70260,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “One World and India”?",
    "answerText": " Arnold Toynbee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70261,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of A Passage to India?",
    "answerText": " E.M. Forster"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70262,
    "questionText": " Central Drug Research Institute is located in ?",
    "answerText": " Lucknow(U.P)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70263,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “A Midsummer Night’s Dream”?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70264,
    "questionText": " Largest reptile is?",
    "answerText": " Crocodile"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70265,
    "questionText": " Armoured Corps Centre and School is located at?",
    "answerText": " Ahmadnagar."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70266,
    "questionText": " Which was the first weekly in Malayalam?",
    "answerText": " Keralamitram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70267,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Harvard Crimson; How Opal Mehta Got Kissed; Got Wild and Got a Life”?",
    "answerText": " Kaavya Viswanathan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70268,
    "questionText": " Brutus; Claudius; Cleopatra",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70269,
    "questionText": " 'Safety Lamp' or 'Davis Lamp' was invented by ?",
    "answerText": " Humphrey Davy in 1816"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70270,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Chidambara smarana”?",
    "answerText": " Balachandran Chullikkadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70271,
    "questionText": " Plants that grow in a dry habitat like deserts and can survive without moisture?",
    "answerText": " Xerophytes."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70272,
    "questionText": " Which city is known as the City of Winds?",
    "answerText": " Chicago"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70273,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Gul-e-Naghma Raghupati”?",
    "answerText": " Sahai Firaq"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70274,
    "questionText": " The School of Scandal ?",
    "answerText": " R.B. Sheridan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70275,
    "questionText": " Which is the most important game of Latin American countries?",
    "answerText": " Soccer (Football)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70276,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Hungry Stones ?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70277,
    "questionText": " The area where Mesopotamian civilisation existed belonged to is now in ?",
    "answerText": " Iraq"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70278,
    "questionText": " Who was the Pope when the Magna Carta was signed in 1215AD?",
    "answerText": " Innocent III"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70279,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Aksharam”?",
    "answerText": " O.N.V Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70280,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Kubla Khan ?",
    "answerText": " Samuel Taylor Coleridge"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70281,
    "questionText": " Uroob is the pen name of?",
    "answerText": " P C Kuttikrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70282,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Sammanam”?",
    "answerText": " Karoor Neelakanda Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70283,
    "questionText": " Largest living Mammal?",
    "answerText": " Blue Whale"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70284,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Brazil?",
    "answerText": " New Cruzado"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70285,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Thirukkural”?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvalluvar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70286,
    "questionText": " An Indian born American biochemist; won Nobel Prize in 1968 for making artificial gene. Who is he ?",
    "answerText": " Har Gobind Khorana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70287,
    "questionText": " Which is the larger sector in developing countries?",
    "answerText": " Primary industry"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70288,
    "questionText": " Rovers Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70289,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Amma”?",
    "answerText": " Balamani Amma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70290,
    "questionText": " Mr. Micawber; Jacob Marley;",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70291,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Magic seeds”?",
    "answerText": " V.S.Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70292,
    "questionText": " Appukili; Ravi; Mollakka",
    "answerText": " OV.Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70293,
    "questionText": " The northern part of Mesopotamia was famously known as ?",
    "answerText": " Assiria"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70294,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Indian Legal System·Can it be saved?",
    "answerText": " Fali S. Nariman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70295,
    "questionText": " Who was the second Malayali to get enrolled in the Indian Cricket Team?",
    "answerText": " Sreesanth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70296,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Don Juan?",
    "answerText": " Lord Byron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70297,
    "questionText": " Which is the only place in Kerala where Uru s (Arabian Trading Vessel) are made?",
    "answerText": " Beypore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70298,
    "questionText": " Who said The desire of power in excess caused the angels to fall; the desire of knowledge in excess caused man to fall?",
    "answerText": " Bacon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70299,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Robinson Crusoe”?",
    "answerText": " Daniel Defoe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70300,
    "questionText": " What is known as the Magnacarta of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Temple Entry Proclamation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70301,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Oh; Calcutta ?",
    "answerText": " Kenneth Tynan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70302,
    "questionText": " Smallest State (India)?",
    "answerText": " Goa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70303,
    "questionText": " Hypothermia is the loss of body heat below?",
    "answerText": " 31.70C"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70304,
    "questionText": " The Japanese Parliament is known as ?",
    "answerText": " Diet"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70305,
    "questionText": " Which King of Travancore made ‘The ‘Janmi-Kudiyam Proclamation’ in 1867 for agrarian reforms?",
    "answerText": " Ayilyam Thirunal."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70306,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Decline of the West ?",
    "answerText": " O. Spengler"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70307,
    "questionText": " Common Cold causing virus is ?",
    "answerText": " Rhinovirus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70308,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Doctor Fuustus”?",
    "answerText": " Christopher Marlowe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70309,
    "questionText": " The Currency of China (People's)?",
    "answerText": " Yuan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70310,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Comedy of Errors”?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70311,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Puerto Rico?",
    "answerText": " San Juan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70312,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the major proponent of free market; arguing against government intervention in a market economy?",
    "answerText": " Milton Friedman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70313,
    "questionText": " Who was the youngest Chief Minister of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " A.K.Antony (37)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70314,
    "questionText": " Indian National Congress started its activities in Travancore during the reign of ?",
    "answerText": " Sri Mulam Thirunal."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70315,
    "questionText": " Which disease is known as Silent Killer ?",
    "answerText": " High blood pressure (Hypertension)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70316,
    "questionText": " First Governor General of Pakistan?",
    "answerText": " Mohammed Ali Jinnah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70317,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Some Inner Fury”?",
    "answerText": " Kamala Markandaya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70318,
    "questionText": " The rate at which World Bank provides loan to underdeveloped countries is?",
    "answerText": 0.055
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70319,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Erne Uppuppaku oru aana undayirunnu “?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammed Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70320,
    "questionText": " Old Secretariat complex started functioning on?",
    "answerText": " 23 August 1869"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70321,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Dr.Zhivago”?",
    "answerText": " Boris Pasternak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70322,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Death of a President”?",
    "answerText": " William Manchester"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70323,
    "questionText": " In which year the Kunjali IV; Muhammed Kunjali was captured by the Zamorin and executed by the Portuguese?",
    "answerText": " 1600 AD"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70324,
    "questionText": " Charles Darwin published his theory of Evolution in his famous book ?",
    "answerText": " On the Origin of Species (1859)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70325,
    "questionText": " Ayyankali He died at the Age of 77on?",
    "answerText": " 18 June 1941."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70326,
    "questionText": " Which is the first tobacco free district in India?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70327,
    "questionText": " Natural sandalwood forests of Kerala is located at?",
    "answerText": " Marayur."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70328,
    "questionText": " Who discovered Smallpox Vaccine (1796)?",
    "answerText": " Edward Jenner"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70329,
    "questionText": " The only district in Kerala where garlic is cultivated?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70330,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Inheritance of Loss”?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Desai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70331,
    "questionText": " The Capital of St. Vincent & The Grenadines?",
    "answerText": " Kingstown"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70332,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “A Passage to England”?",
    "answerText": " Nirad C.Chowdhury"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70333,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Cat is?",
    "answerText": " Felis domesticus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70334,
    "questionText": " National Literacy Mission (NLM)was launched in?",
    "answerText": 1998
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70335,
    "questionText": " The concept of Rolling Plan was introduced by ?",
    "answerText": " Gunnar Myrdal in his famous work Asian Drama"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70336,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Christian”",
    "answerText": " John Bunyan."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70337,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Qatar?",
    "answerText": " Qatari Riyal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70338,
    "questionText": " Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) was formed in ?",
    "answerText": 1964
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70339,
    "questionText": " Euro coins and banknotes entered circulation on ?",
    "answerText": " 1st Jan 2002"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70340,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Tempest;?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70341,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tirayum Chuzhiyum”?",
    "answerText": " Prof. S. Guptan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70342,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Rip Van Winkle?",
    "answerText": " Washington Irving"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70343,
    "questionText": " First Indian to scale Mount Everest?",
    "answerText": " Phu Dorjee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70344,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Odakkuzhal “?",
    "answerText": " G. Sankara Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70345,
    "questionText": " The Versailles city is in ?",
    "answerText": " France near Paris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70346,
    "questionText": " Which was the first University in France?",
    "answerText": " Paris University"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70347,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ A House for Mr. Biswas”?",
    "answerText": " V.S.Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70348,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “His Excellency”?",
    "answerText": " Emile Zola"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70349,
    "questionText": " Semitic; Hemitic and Indo-Europeans are the subgroups of which race ?",
    "answerText": " Caucasoid race"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70350,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Dominica?",
    "answerText": " Roseau"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70351,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of In Light of lndia?",
    "answerText": " Octavia Paz"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70352,
    "questionText": " Which place is known as the Cultural Capital of Kerala ?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70353,
    "questionText": " Who is the only person to hold the office of MLA; MP; Speaker; Minister; Deputy Chief Minister and Chief Minister?",
    "answerText": " C.H. Muhammad Koya."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70354,
    "questionText": " The term bank is derived from 'banco'; from ?",
    "answerText": " Italian word for 'bench'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70355,
    "questionText": " Name the machine used to break up kidneystones by ultra sound waves?",
    "answerText": " Lithotripter"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70356,
    "questionText": " Kerala Minerals and Metals is at?",
    "answerText": " Chavara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70357,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Glimpses of World History”?",
    "answerText": " Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70358,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Hamlet”?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70359,
    "questionText": " The percentage of tannin contained in Tea leaves is?",
    "answerText": 0.18
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70360,
    "questionText": " The construction of Old Secretariat complex was carried out by?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70361,
    "questionText": " Who said ‘We live in a wonderful world that is full of beauty; charm and adventure There is no end to the adventures that -we can have if only we seek them with our eyes open’?",
    "answerText": " Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70362,
    "questionText": " BIOS stands for ?",
    "answerText": " Basic Input/Output System"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70363,
    "questionText": " Mussolini was captured and killed at?",
    "answerText": " Como"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70364,
    "questionText": " Land of White Elephant?",
    "answerText": " Thailand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70365,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters “Brutus; Claudius; Cleopatra”",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70366,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Madagascar?",
    "answerText": " Antananarivo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70367,
    "questionText": " The B-programming language was developed by ?",
    "answerText": " Ken Thompson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70368,
    "questionText": " City of Skyscrapers?",
    "answerText": " New York (USA)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70369,
    "questionText": " District of Columbia (Washington DC); America’s capital district is on the banks of the river ?",
    "answerText": " Potomak river"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70370,
    "questionText": " Which was the first film studio in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " The Travancore National pictures established by JC Daniel in 1926 in Nagarcoil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70371,
    "questionText": " Lal Bahadur Shastri National Academy ofAdministration is located at?",
    "answerText": " Ghaziabad (Uttar Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70372,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Pilgrim’s Progress”?",
    "answerText": " John Bunyan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70373,
    "questionText": " Nasik is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Godavari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70374,
    "questionText": " During which age 'Potters Wheel' was invented?",
    "answerText": " Neolithic Age"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70375,
    "questionText": " Father of Immunology?",
    "answerText": " Edward Jenner"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70376,
    "questionText": " Plants growing well in full sunlight are called?",
    "answerText": " Helio-phytes."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70377,
    "questionText": " “Cell” which is the smallest and fundamental unit of life was discovered by?",
    "answerText": " Robert Hook in 1665 and published under the title Micrographia."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70378,
    "questionText": " Where is the first Biological Park in India set up?",
    "answerText": " Agastiarkudam in Thiruvananthapuram on I January 1992"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70379,
    "questionText": " Centre for Cellular and Molecular biology is located in ?",
    "answerText": " Hyderabad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70380,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Costa Rica?",
    "answerText": " San Jose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70381,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “E. V Kathakal and MLC Kathakal.”?",
    "answerText": " E.Y.Krishana Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70382,
    "questionText": " Vascoda Gama was buried at St. Francis Church in the year?",
    "answerText": 1524
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70383,
    "questionText": " Kathakali was developed by?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70384,
    "questionText": " TB vaccine was discovered by ?",
    "answerText": " Leon Calmette and Camille Guerin (1992)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70385,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Childe Harold”?",
    "answerText": " Lord Byron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70386,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “French Mystic”?",
    "answerText": " Romain Rolland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70387,
    "questionText": " , Which is the first college Magazine in the state?",
    "answerText": " Vidyasamgraham {a publication of CMS College started in 1864 }"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70388,
    "questionText": " The process of sudden heritable change in a gene due to change in its composition is called ?",
    "answerText": " Mutation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70389,
    "questionText": " Bartholomew Diaz sailed down the west coast of Africa in 1487; which came to be known as ?",
    "answerText": " 'Cape of Good Hope'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70390,
    "questionText": " Where is the most popular tourist destination Promenade Beach?",
    "answerText": " Pondicherry"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70391,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ A Train to Pakistan”?",
    "answerText": " Khushwant Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70392,
    "questionText": " What is the real name of George Eliot?",
    "answerText": " Mary Ann Evans"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70393,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “St.John”?",
    "answerText": " G.B.Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70394,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Sadar-i-Riyasat”?",
    "answerText": " Karan Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70395,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Step Across This Line”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70396,
    "questionText": " Which Cherala ruler adopted the title Imaya Varampan?",
    "answerText": " Nedum Cheralathan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70397,
    "questionText": " In which year Pincode system was started in Kerala?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70398,
    "questionText": " The quantity of blood in the body of a healthy person is?",
    "answerText": " 5-6 Iitres"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70399,
    "questionText": " In which year a ship first crossed the Atlantic?",
    "answerText": 1833
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70400,
    "questionText": " Record of the oral part of history is called?",
    "answerText": " Saga"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70401,
    "questionText": " Which is the biggest fort in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Bekal Fort"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70402,
    "questionText": " Gonorrhoea causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Neisseria Gonorhoeae"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70403,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Alphabet of Lust ?",
    "answerText": " Kamala Das"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70404,
    "questionText": " Which subject was known as Queen of Sciences during the Middle Ages?",
    "answerText": " Theology"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70405,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Oedipus”",
    "answerText": " Sophocles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70406,
    "questionText": " The Cunieform script was discovered by?",
    "answerText": " Sumerians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70407,
    "questionText": " The German plan of conquering Britain during the Second World War was known as ?",
    "answerText": " 'Sea - Lion'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70408,
    "questionText": " The first post office in Kerala was started in?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha district"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70409,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Indian War of Independence”?",
    "answerText": " V.D.Savarkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70410,
    "questionText": " 'Utopia' was a famous work of ?",
    "answerText": " Sir Thomas More(portraying an ideal community on an imaginary island indicating the glaring abuses of his time)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70411,
    "questionText": " Colour of the skin is due to the presence of?",
    "answerText": " melanin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70412,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Xerox?",
    "answerText": " Haloid-Xerox"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70413,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “My South Block years”?",
    "answerText": " J N. Dixit"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70414,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Cancer Ward”?",
    "answerText": " Alexander Solzhenitsyn"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70415,
    "questionText": " Energy is stored in the mitochondria as ?",
    "answerText": " ATP molecules"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70416,
    "questionText": " Sankaracharya founded four mutts in four comers of India;They are?",
    "answerText": " Badrinath in the North (Jyotir Mutt) Purl in the east (Govardhan) Dwaraka in the West (Sarada Mutt) and Sringeri in the south."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70417,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Gulliver”",
    "answerText": " Jonathan Swift"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70418,
    "questionText": " Cuttack is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Mahanadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70419,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Around the World in Eighty Days ?",
    "answerText": " Jules Verne"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70420,
    "questionText": " The agitation known as Vimochana Samaram or 'Liberation struggle' began on ?",
    "answerText": " 12-Jun-59"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70421,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Punjab The Knight of Falsehood”?",
    "answerText": " K.P.SGiII"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70422,
    "questionText": " In which year the Malayalam Manorama was converted to a daily?",
    "answerText": 1928
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70423,
    "questionText": " Human Equator of the Earth?",
    "answerText": " Himalayas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70424,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Step Across This Line”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70425,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Time Machine?",
    "answerText": " H.G Wells"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70426,
    "questionText": " Which places are known as the Kodaikanals in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kuttikkanam and Wagamon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70427,
    "questionText": " The period of long sleep for animals in cold weather when there is no food available is known as ?",
    "answerText": " Hibernation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70428,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Rubber (tyres)?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hancock"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70429,
    "questionText": " Who is the first Japanese to win the Nobel Prize in 1968 for literature?",
    "answerText": " Kawabata Yasunari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70430,
    "questionText": " Kotah is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Chambal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70431,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Germany (United)?",
    "answerText": " Berlin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70432,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Speed Post”?",
    "answerText": " Shobha De"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70433,
    "questionText": " To which race Ay dynasty belonged to ?",
    "answerText": " Yadava race."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70434,
    "questionText": " Which is the first Police Museum in India?",
    "answerText": " The Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Police Museum; Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70435,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Vitamins?",
    "answerText": " Funk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70436,
    "questionText": " Chattampi Swami Memorial is situated at ?",
    "answerText": " Panmana."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70437,
    "questionText": " Headquarters or Rubber Board is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70438,
    "questionText": " The district with least number of panchyats and villages is?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70439,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Odayil Ninnu”?",
    "answerText": " P. Kesava Dev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70440,
    "questionText": " Elephant tusks are enlarged ?",
    "answerText": " Incisors"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70441,
    "questionText": " Who was the Diwan of Marthanda Varma ?",
    "answerText": " Ramayyan Dalawa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70442,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Chitra ?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70443,
    "questionText": " Who collect impure blood from the tissues and carry it to the heart?",
    "answerText": " Veins"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70444,
    "questionText": " Land of Golden Fleece?",
    "answerText": " Australia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70445,
    "questionText": " Longest Day?",
    "answerText": " June 21 (in Northern Hemisphere)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70446,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Marapavagal”?",
    "answerText": " Karoor Neelakanda Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70447,
    "questionText": " Play Ground of Europe?",
    "answerText": " Switzerland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70448,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Second World War?",
    "answerText": " Winston Churchill"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70449,
    "questionText": " Shenduruny wildlife sanctuary is situated in?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70450,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Virginians;The ?",
    "answerText": " William Thackeray"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70451,
    "questionText": " Athens; Sparta; Corinth; Thebes; Mascedonia were the major city states in ?",
    "answerText": " Greece"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70452,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Oxygen?",
    "answerText": " J.B.Priestley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70453,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ In a Free State”?",
    "answerText": " V.S.Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70454,
    "questionText": " New Orleans is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Mississippi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70455,
    "questionText": " How many members participated in the Pattini Jatha' led by A.K. Gopalan?",
    "answerText": 32
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70456,
    "questionText": " The percentage of Lactose contained in Mother's milk is.?",
    "answerText": 0.07
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70457,
    "questionText": " In the first quarter of the 17th century some protestants from England migrated to the souththern part of North America to escape from the religious persecution of James I. They came to be known as ?",
    "answerText": " Pilgrim fathers"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70458,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Bitter Sweet”?",
    "answerText": " Noel Coward"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70459,
    "questionText": " The first railway line in Kerala was between?",
    "answerText": " Tirur and Beypur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70460,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Airship (Non-rigid)?",
    "answerText": " Zeppelin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70461,
    "questionText": " Who is the King of England who summoned the ‘Long Parliament’?",
    "answerText": " Charles I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70462,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Modern Painters”?",
    "answerText": " John Ruskin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70463,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Indulekha”?",
    "answerText": " Oyarathu Chandu Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70464,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Comedy of Errors ?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70465,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ramayana Darshanam”?",
    "answerText": " K.V.Puttappa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70466,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Moor's Last Sigh”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70467,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Swami and Friends”?",
    "answerText": " R.K.Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70468,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “East of Aden”?",
    "answerText": " John Steinbeck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70469,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Neon Lamp?",
    "answerText": " George Clande"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70470,
    "questionText": " First Indian Woman to go in space?",
    "answerText": " Kalpana Chawla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70471,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Chandalika”?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70472,
    "questionText": " Russian Revolution was started in the year ?",
    "answerText": 1917
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70473,
    "questionText": " Which is the most widely spoken language in Latin America?",
    "answerText": " Spanish"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70474,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Ottayadipatha”?",
    "answerText": " Madhavikutty (Kamala Surayya)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70475,
    "questionText": " Plants contain one of the polysaccharide in the cell wall in form of ?",
    "answerText": " Cellulose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70476,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Genetic Code (deciphering)?",
    "answerText": " Hargobind Khorana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70477,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Utopia”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas More"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70478,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ India- The Critical years”?",
    "answerText": " Kuldip Nayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70479,
    "questionText": " Law of Demand was introduced by ?",
    "answerText": " Alfred Marshall"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70480,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Swami and Friends”?",
    "answerText": " R.K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70481,
    "questionText": " Name the Chinese space shuttle in which Yang Liwei; its first space traveller travelled?",
    "answerText": " Zhenshou V"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70482,
    "questionText": " Who was the publisher Keralamitram newspaper from Kochi?",
    "answerText": " Devji Bhimji a Gujarathi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70483,
    "questionText": " National Biological Laboratory (in Planning) is located at?",
    "answerText": " Palampur; Kangra Dist. (Himachal Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70484,
    "questionText": " The Proclamation of lndependent Travancore was made by?",
    "answerText": " Sir. C.P.Ramaswami Ayyer."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70485,
    "questionText": " Name the first American President who was the son of a former president?",
    "answerText": " John Kwinsy Adams"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70486,
    "questionText": " The year in which Israel was formed in Palestine?",
    "answerText": 1948
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70487,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Chandalika?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70488,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Cyprus?",
    "answerText": " Nicosia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70489,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “.First Among Equals”?",
    "answerText": " Joffery Archer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70490,
    "questionText": " ..............is drug that acts on central nervous system and is used to calm; decrease anxiety or help a person to sleep?",
    "answerText": " Tranquilizer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70491,
    "questionText": " Largest Road (India)?",
    "answerText": " Grand Trunk Road"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70492,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Metamorphosis ?",
    "answerText": " Franz Kafka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70493,
    "questionText": " Sterilization process in male is called ?",
    "answerText": " Vasectomy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70494,
    "questionText": " Flying fox is kind of ?",
    "answerText": " Bat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70495,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Death in Venice ?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Mann"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70496,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Indo-Pakistan Conflict ?",
    "answerText": " The Russel Brines"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70497,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Rajpath Se Lokpath Par”?",
    "answerText": " A.B.Vajpayee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70498,
    "questionText": " Venadu;Kuttanadu; Kudanadu; Puzhinadu and Karkanad were the five divisions of Kerala in ?",
    "answerText": " The Sangham Age."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70499,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Mahabharatham Kilippattu”?",
    "answerText": " Ezhuthachan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70500,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Mexico?",
    "answerText": " Peso"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70501,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kamasutra”?",
    "answerText": " Vatsyayana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70502,
    "questionText": " Hyder Ali conquered Bekal Fort in?",
    "answerText": 1763
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70503,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Spain?",
    "answerText": " Madrid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70504,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Tharavadu and Oru Muri Tenga “?",
    "answerText": " P. Kesava Dev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70505,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Passage to India”?",
    "answerText": " E.M. Forster"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70506,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “West Wind”?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70507,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Three Sisters?",
    "answerText": " Anton Chekov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70508,
    "questionText": " Founders of' Yahoo are?",
    "answerText": " Jerri Yang and David Filo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70509,
    "questionText": " The Petition of Rights was accepted by the British Parliament in ?",
    "answerText": 1628
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70510,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Vatican City State?",
    "answerText": " Lira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70511,
    "questionText": " Name the American Presidents who got Nobel Prize for Peace?",
    "answerText": " Theodor Roosevelt; Jimmy Carter; Wudrow Wilson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70512,
    "questionText": " Thrissur Pooram was commenced by?",
    "answerText": " Sakthan Thampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70513,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of One World and India ?",
    "answerText": " Arnold Toynbee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70514,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Panama?",
    "answerText": " Panama City"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70515,
    "questionText": " First American to win Nobel Prize for Peace?",
    "answerText": " Theodor Roosevelt (1906)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70516,
    "questionText": " The ruler who brought liberalist policies in China in 1970 is?",
    "answerText": " Den-Sia-Ping"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70517,
    "questionText": " On defeat Paliyat Achan was deported to?",
    "answerText": " Madras."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70518,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Confession of a lover”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70519,
    "questionText": " Kollam Era was started in ?",
    "answerText": " AD 825 (August 15) (Chingam 1)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70520,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Yakshi”?",
    "answerText": " Malayattoor Ramakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70521,
    "questionText": " Which war was fought as 'a war to end all wars'?",
    "answerText": " The First World War"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70522,
    "questionText": " Presence of excess urea in the blood ?",
    "answerText": " Uremia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70523,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Umakeralam”?",
    "answerText": " Uloor S Parameshwara Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70524,
    "questionText": " Who was the fourth and last Kunjali?",
    "answerText": " Muhammed Kunjali."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70525,
    "questionText": " Chirutha; classipper",
    "answerText": " Thakazhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70526,
    "questionText": " Which country is known as the Cradle of Renaissance?",
    "answerText": " Italy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70527,
    "questionText": " Which is the oldest European structure in India?",
    "answerText": " Pallipuram Fort;also known as Ayakotta or Azhikotta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70528,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Last Man in Tower”?",
    "answerText": " Arvind Adiga"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70529,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Between the lines”?",
    "answerText": " Kuldip Nayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70530,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Julius Caeser”?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70531,
    "questionText": " Yankee Stadium (New York) is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Boxing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70532,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Guide”?",
    "answerText": " R.K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70533,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Less Miserables’?",
    "answerText": " Victor Hugo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70534,
    "questionText": " Name the year in which the Decimal system of coinage was introduced in India?",
    "answerText": 1957
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70535,
    "questionText": " National Blood Donation Day is on ?",
    "answerText": " October I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70536,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Crescent Moon”?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70537,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Untouchable”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70538,
    "questionText": " Abraham Lincoln was assassinated by ?",
    "answerText": " John Wllksbooth (in 1865 while watching a drama; Our American Cousin' in the Fords Theatre along with his wife)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70539,
    "questionText": " Currency coins are known as ?",
    "answerText": " Legal tender money"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70540,
    "questionText": " The 'General Theory of Employment; Interestand Money’ is formulated by?",
    "answerText": " John Maynard Keynes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70541,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Songs of India ?",
    "answerText": " Sarojini Naidu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70542,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Doctor's Dilemma ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70543,
    "questionText": " Which is the autobiography of Adolf Hitler?",
    "answerText": " Mein Kampf(My Struggle)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70544,
    "questionText": " Diptheria causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Comeye bacterium diptheriae"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70545,
    "questionText": " The first book in Malayalam ‘Samkshepa Vedartham’ was written by?",
    "answerText": " Clement Piyanus Pathiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70546,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Anna Karenina",
    "answerText": " Leo Tolstoy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70547,
    "questionText": " HDI stands for?",
    "answerText": " Human Development Index"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70548,
    "questionText": " Formation of Kerala State was in ?",
    "answerText": 1956
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70549,
    "questionText": " Who is known as father of German Unity?",
    "answerText": " Helmet Kohl"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70550,
    "questionText": " Presence of urea in the blood is called ?",
    "answerText": " Uremia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70551,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Father of Video games?",
    "answerText": " Ralph Baer."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70552,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Satyartha Prakash”?",
    "answerText": " Swami Dayananda Saraswathi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70553,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “From Surprise to Victory”?",
    "answerText": " Gen. V.P. Malik"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70554,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Mitochondria?",
    "answerText": " C.Benda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70555,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Malavikagnimitra?",
    "answerText": " Kalidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70556,
    "questionText": " 1Kilobyte= ?",
    "answerText": " 1024 Bytes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70557,
    "questionText": " Experiments with Plant Hybrids is a book by ?",
    "answerText": " Rev. Gregor Mendel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70558,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Shah Nama”?",
    "answerText": " Firdausi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70559,
    "questionText": " Who was the first woman to become the Vice Chancellor of Cambridge University ?",
    "answerText": " Aleson Richard"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70560,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “A Gift of Wings”?",
    "answerText": " Shanti Gopalan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70561,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Philippines?",
    "answerText": " Peso"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70562,
    "questionText": " The Capital of San Marino?",
    "answerText": " San Marino"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70563,
    "questionText": " Key to Mediterranean?",
    "answerText": " Gibraltar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70564,
    "questionText": " The acronym DBMS stands for what?",
    "answerText": " Data Based Management System"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70565,
    "questionText": " The Two Trillion Dollar Meltdown was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Charles R. Morris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70566,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Mango is?",
    "answerText": " Mangifera Indica"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70567,
    "questionText": " First Women Grandmaster?",
    "answerText": " Ms. Vijayalakshmi (India)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70568,
    "questionText": " Who was the ruling king of France when the revolution broke out (1774-1792)?",
    "answerText": " Louis XVI"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70569,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Banker to the poor-The story of the Grameen Bank?",
    "answerText": " Muhammad Yunus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70570,
    "questionText": " World Book Day and Copyright Day is on?",
    "answerText": " April 23 "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70571,
    "questionText": " Name the American President who worked as the Chairman of UN Human Rights Committee?",
    "answerText": " Elenar Roosevelt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70572,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Post Office?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70573,
    "questionText": " Communist Manifesto was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Karl Marx and Fredrik Engels"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70574,
    "questionText": " Rubber is obtained from the latex of ?",
    "answerText": " Hevea brasiliensis."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70575,
    "questionText": " Which country is geographically situated in the Ring of fire?",
    "answerText": " Japan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70576,
    "questionText": " The Capital of China?",
    "answerText": " Beijing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70577,
    "questionText": " The most important stimulant in coffee leaves is?",
    "answerText": " Caffeine."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70578,
    "questionText": " First important Trade Union Movement in the world was ?",
    "answerText": " Chartist Movement originated in England as a result of the Industrial Revolution"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70579,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Blood Transfusion?",
    "answerText": " Landsteneir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70580,
    "questionText": " In which place Lal Bahadur Shastri died?",
    "answerText": " At Tashkent"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70581,
    "questionText": " Botulism causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Clostridium botulinum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70582,
    "questionText": " Hatsheput Who is considered as the first women ruler of the world ?",
    "answerText": " Egyptian Queen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70583,
    "questionText": " Indian Institute of Chemical Biology is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kolkata (West Bengal)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70584,
    "questionText": " Which was the first News paper?",
    "answerText": " Rajyasamacharam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70585,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Bhakti Yoga ?",
    "answerText": " Swami Vivekananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70586,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Netaji Dead or Alive ?",
    "answerText": " Samar Guha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70587,
    "questionText": " In Vallisnaria pollination occurs by?",
    "answerText": " Water"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70588,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Chief Minister of 'Thiru-Kochi State?",
    "answerText": " T.K. Narayana Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70589,
    "questionText": " Longest Steel Arch Bridge?",
    "answerText": " New River Gorge Bridge; 518.2 m long (West Virginia; USA)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70590,
    "questionText": " Where did Chatampi Swamikal attained Samadhi?",
    "answerText": " At Panmana in Kollam district."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70591,
    "questionText": " Largest Mosque?",
    "answerText": " Umayyad Mosque 157 m × 97 m covering an area of 3.76 acres. Damascus; Syria."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70592,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Turbine Engine?",
    "answerText": " Charles Parsons"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70593,
    "questionText": " UnionTerritory of Lakshadweep is under the jurisdiction of which High Court?",
    "answerText": " Kerala High Court"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70594,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Horse is?",
    "answerText": " Equus caballus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70595,
    "questionText": " The International Film Festival of Kerala, started in 1996, is held annually in?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70596,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Little Corporal?",
    "answerText": " Napolean"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70597,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Nepal?",
    "answerText": " Nepalese Rupee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70598,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Viswavikya thamaya Mooku”?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammed Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70599,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “‘The Count of Monte Cristo’”?",
    "answerText": " Alexander Dumas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70600,
    "questionText": " In which year the Turks captured Constantinople?",
    "answerText": 453
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70601,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Air Plane (Jet Engine)?",
    "answerText": " Whittle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70602,
    "questionText": " Velu Thampi was appointed as Mulakumadiseela Karyakar (Commercial minister) in 1799 by?",
    "answerText": " Balaramavarma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70603,
    "questionText": " National Metallurgical Laboratory is located at?",
    "answerText": " Jamshedpur (Bihar)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70604,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Heat and Dust”?",
    "answerText": " Ruth P. Jhabwala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70605,
    "questionText": " Stock exchange Index of London is?",
    "answerText": " FTSE"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70606,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Candida ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70607,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Sense and Sensibility?",
    "answerText": " Jane Austen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70608,
    "questionText": " How many persons sighed in The Malayali Memorial ?",
    "answerText": " 10;028"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70609,
    "questionText": " Sankaracharya (788 - 820 AD) the great Advaita philosopher was an younger contemporary of ?",
    "answerText": " Kulasekhara Alwar."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70610,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Jane Eyre ?",
    "answerText": " Charlotte Bronte"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70611,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Kapala Kendala ?",
    "answerText": " Bankim Chandra Chatterjee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70612,
    "questionText": " Which is a scheme of AMMA for giving monthly stipend to actors who are at their elder ages or are suffering from serious diseases?",
    "answerText": " Kaineettam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70613,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Broken Wing”?",
    "answerText": " Sarojini Naidu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70614,
    "questionText": " The revolt against the 4I year long ruled Muammer Gaddafi in Libya began on?",
    "answerText": " February 15 -2011"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70615,
    "questionText": " Prithi Singh Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Polo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70616,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Major Barbara ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70617,
    "questionText": " Anaxagoras and Euclid were famous Mathematicians from ?",
    "answerText": " Greek"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70618,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Alice”",
    "answerText": " Lewis Carroll"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70619,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of India for a Billion Reasons?",
    "answerText": " Amit Dasgupta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70620,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Geiger counter?",
    "answerText": " Geiger"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70621,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Vinay Patrika”?",
    "answerText": " Tulsidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70622,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Much Ado About Nothing”?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70623,
    "questionText": " How many countries are members of ADB?",
    "answerText": " 67 members - of which 48 are from within Asia and the Pacific and 19 outside"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70624,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Wilhelm Meister”?",
    "answerText": " Goethe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70625,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Pilgrim's Progress”?",
    "answerText": " John Bunyan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70626,
    "questionText": " Who was the first European to reach Latin America ?",
    "answerText": " Christopher Columbus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70627,
    "questionText": " Largest Stadium?",
    "answerText": " Strahov Stadium. It can accommodate around 240; 000 people in Prague; Czech"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70628,
    "questionText": " Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology is located at?",
    "answerText": " Hyderabad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70629,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Comedy of Erros”?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70630,
    "questionText": " Plants which trap insects and other small creatures on their sticky leaves?",
    "answerText": " Carnivorous plants Ex Venus- fly trap"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70631,
    "questionText": " Who was the First Malayali Swimmer to participate in Olympic Games?",
    "answerText": " Sebastian Xavier"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70632,
    "questionText": " Greek critics considered ……as the aim of tragedies?",
    "answerText": " Catharsis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70633,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Baalyakaala Sakhi’?",
    "answerText": " Vaikkom Muhammad Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70634,
    "questionText": " Anglicanism was led in England by ?",
    "answerText": " King Henry VlII and Queen Elizabeth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70635,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Much Ado About Nothing?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70636,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Past and Present?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Carlyle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70637,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Jaguar Smile”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70638,
    "questionText": " Dance form in Mexico is known as ?",
    "answerText": " Jarabe Tapatio"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70639,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ I am not an island”?",
    "answerText": " K.A.Abbas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70640,
    "questionText": " On which mountain the figures of four American Presidents are engraved ?",
    "answerText": " Mount Rushmor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70641,
    "questionText": " The Currency of El Salvador?",
    "answerText": " Colon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70642,
    "questionText": " Who said ‘The remedy is worse than the disease’?",
    "answerText": " Bacon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70643,
    "questionText": " The viruses eating (destroying) bacteria and were invented by d'Herelle ?",
    "answerText": " Bacteriophages"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70644,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Letter from Peking”?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70645,
    "questionText": " The first Atom Bomb was dropped in Hiroshima by America on ?",
    "answerText": " August 6; 1945."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70646,
    "questionText": " By which treaty Kayarnkulam became a vassal of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Treaty of Mannar (1742)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70647,
    "questionText": " Who discovered West Indies and thought it was India in 1492?",
    "answerText": " Christopher Columbus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70648,
    "questionText": " Tetanus causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Clostridium tetani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70649,
    "questionText": " National Dairy Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Karnal (Haryana)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70650,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Bitter Sweet?",
    "answerText": " Noel Coward"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70651,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ The Ground Beneath her Feet”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70652,
    "questionText": " Who questioned the Sale of Indulgence?",
    "answerText": " Martin Luther"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70653,
    "questionText": " Punalur Plywood Factory was started during the period of?",
    "answerText": " Sri Chitra Thirunal."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70654,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Alphabet of Lust”?",
    "answerText": " Kamala Das"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70655,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of White House Years?",
    "answerText": " Henry Kissinger"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70656,
    "questionText": " The Krishnapuram Palace near Kayalamkulam was built by?",
    "answerText": " MarthaiKlavarma."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70657,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Laws Versus Justice”?",
    "answerText": " V.R.Krishna Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70658,
    "questionText": " In which centuryBuddhism reached Kerala?",
    "answerText": " 3rd century-BC (232BC) during the period of Ashoka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70659,
    "questionText": " Mac Mohan Line separates?",
    "answerText": " India and China"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70660,
    "questionText": " A market condition of ’Number of sellers – Few; Number of buyers – Large’ is known as?",
    "answerText": " Oligopoly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70661,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Chiriyum Chinthayum”?",
    "answerText": " E.Y.Krishana Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70662,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Digital Fortress”?",
    "answerText": " Dan Brown"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70663,
    "questionText": " Nationalisation of Suez Canal was done by?",
    "answerText": " Col.Gamal Abdul Nazar of Egypt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70664,
    "questionText": " Name of French currency is?",
    "answerText": " Franc"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70665,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “French Revolution”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Carlyle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70666,
    "questionText": " President who abolished slavery in America was ?",
    "answerText": " Abraham Lincoln"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70667,
    "questionText": " X-Ray was discovered by?",
    "answerText": " Wilhelm Roentgen in1895"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70668,
    "questionText": " Which element helps in the fruit forming stage in plants?",
    "answerText": " Potassium"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70669,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Kadambari ?",
    "answerText": " Bana Bhatt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70670,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Decline of the West”?",
    "answerText": " O.Spengier"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70671,
    "questionText": " Which is the Asia's largest cinnamon estate?",
    "answerText": " Anjarakandy (Kannur)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70672,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ The Namesake”?",
    "answerText": " Jumpa Lahiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70673,
    "questionText": " Who was the founder of the science fiction novel?",
    "answerText": " Jules Verne"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70674,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of X-ray?",
    "answerText": " Roentgen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70675,
    "questionText": " Largest Light House (World)?",
    "answerText": " Bishop Rock (England)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70676,
    "questionText": " Plants growing in marsh are called?",
    "answerText": " Helophytes."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70677,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Fall ofa Sparrow?",
    "answerText": " Salim Ali "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70678,
    "questionText": " The famous saying I came; 1saw; 1conquered' is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Julius Caesar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70679,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Twenty Years After ?",
    "answerText": " Alexander Dumas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70680,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Fairie Queene”?",
    "answerText": " Edmund Spenser"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70681,
    "questionText": " Testosterone which affects male reproductory; is produced by?",
    "answerText": " Testes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70682,
    "questionText": " Which King of Travancore started the Ayurveda College at Trivandrum?",
    "answerText": " Sri Mulam Thirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70683,
    "questionText": " The involuntary actions of the body is controlled by?",
    "answerText": " Medulla oblongata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70684,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Leela”?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70685,
    "questionText": " The IMF and the World Bank (IBRD) came into existence as a result of ?",
    "answerText": " The Bretton Woods Conference"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70686,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Guyana?",
    "answerText": " Georgetown"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70687,
    "questionText": " Argumentative Indian was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70688,
    "questionText": " First detecting of AIDS Case in India was from ?",
    "answerText": " Chennai in 1986."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70689,
    "questionText": " The famous Koodalmanikyam Temple at Irinjalakkuda; dedicated to Bharata was a famous?",
    "answerText": " Jain temple."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70690,
    "questionText": " The Palakkad fort was built by ?",
    "answerText": " Haider Ali."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70691,
    "questionText": " Controlling centre of the cell is ?",
    "answerText": " Nucleus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70692,
    "questionText": " Tuberculin Test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Tuberculosis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70693,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Micky Mouse?",
    "answerText": " Walt Disney"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70694,
    "questionText": " Country ousted from League of Nations in 1939 ?",
    "answerText": " U.S.S.R"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70695,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Australia?",
    "answerText": " Canberra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70696,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “It is Always Possible”?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70697,
    "questionText": " Headquarters of World Bank (IBRD) is at?",
    "answerText": " Washington; (USA)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70698,
    "questionText": " Which was the first Indian state to accept tourism, as an industry?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70699,
    "questionText": " After retirement justice M. Fathima Beevi became the Governor of?",
    "answerText": " Tamil Nadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70700,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Memories of World War II”?",
    "answerText": " Winston Churchill"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70701,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of A Week with Gandhi ?",
    "answerText": " Louis Fischer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70702,
    "questionText": " Appunni; Amarsingh;",
    "answerText": " M.T. Vasudevan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70703,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Seychelles?",
    "answerText": " Victoria"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70704,
    "questionText": " Who organised a Hussur Kachery at Kollam?",
    "answerText": " Velu Tampi Dalawa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70705,
    "questionText": " A blog comprising video is called ?",
    "answerText": " Vlog"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70706,
    "questionText": " Sericulture is?",
    "answerText": " Rearing of silk worms."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70707,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “As You Like It”?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70708,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Bell Jar”?",
    "answerText": " Sylvia Plath"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70709,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Czechoslovakia?",
    "answerText": " Koruna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70710,
    "questionText": " Who was the First Keralite Athlete to participate in Olympics?",
    "answerText": " Suresh Babu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70711,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ramayana”?",
    "answerText": " Valmiki (in Sanskrit)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70712,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Tyre (Pneumatic)?",
    "answerText": " Dunlop"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70713,
    "questionText": " Kunjalis were four in number. Who was the first Kunjali?",
    "answerText": " Kutti Ali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70714,
    "questionText": " Who is the founder of Twitter ?",
    "answerText": " Ivan Williams"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70715,
    "questionText": " Which is the first Malayalam film to win the National Film Award for Best feature film?",
    "answerText": " Chemmeen {based on a story by Thakazhi Sivasankara Pillai}"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70716,
    "questionText": " City of Seven Hills?",
    "answerText": " Rome (Italy)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70717,
    "questionText": " Which is the world's first film with a single actor in the star cast?",
    "answerText": " The Guard (2001)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70718,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Testament of Beauty”?",
    "answerText": " Robert Bridges"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70719,
    "questionText": " Which was a gold coin of ancient Kerala believed to have been introduced by Parasurama. ?",
    "answerText": " 'Rasi’"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70720,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Indian Philosophy”?",
    "answerText": " Dr.S.Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70721,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Man and Superman ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70722,
    "questionText": " The Chinese Revolution took place in ?",
    "answerText": 1911
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70723,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Naganandan King ?",
    "answerText": " Harsha Vardhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70724,
    "questionText": " Merdeka is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football (Asian)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70725,
    "questionText": " Who succeeded Marthandavarma to the throne of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Karthika Tirunal Rama Varma (Dharmaraja)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70726,
    "questionText": " Sadhujana Paripalana Sangham was later renamed as?",
    "answerText": " Pulaya Mahasabha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70727,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Human Knowledge ?",
    "answerText": " Bertrand Russell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70728,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tulsi Sat Sai”?",
    "answerText": " Tulsidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70729,
    "questionText": " Inter-relationship of DNA; RNA and Protein commonly called ?",
    "answerText": " Central Dogma of life."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70730,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Erupathinalu Vrutham”?",
    "answerText": " Ezhuthachan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70731,
    "questionText": " Economic botany is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Study of plants of economic use or value"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70732,
    "questionText": " Dr. B.C. Roy Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " National Football (Junior)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70733,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Onakazhcha”?",
    "answerText": " Lalitham bika Antharjenam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70734,
    "questionText": " The thermoregulatory centre of the human body is?",
    "answerText": " Hypothalamus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70735,
    "questionText": " Which boundary line separates America and Canada?",
    "answerText": " 49th Parallel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70736,
    "questionText": " The condition when haemoglobin content of the blood falls below normal is termed?",
    "answerText": " Anaemia."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70737,
    "questionText": " Which year India government formally launched Pulse Polio Campaign?",
    "answerText": 1994
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70738,
    "questionText": " The Malabar Rebellion was in?",
    "answerText": 1921
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70739,
    "questionText": " Which is a popular ritual form of worship of North Malabar in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Theyyam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70740,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the Father of history?",
    "answerText": " Herodotus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70741,
    "questionText": " The technique of printing was first developed by ?",
    "answerText": " The Chinese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70742,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Shalimar”?",
    "answerText": " Manohar Malgonkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70743,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Third World in the Age of Globalisation”?",
    "answerText": " Ash Narain Roy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70744,
    "questionText": " Chakola Gold Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70745,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Aeneid”?",
    "answerText": " Virgil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70746,
    "questionText": " Coldest Place (World)?",
    "answerText": " Ve r k h o y a n s k (Siberia) –85O"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70747,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Ukraine?",
    "answerText": " Kiev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70748,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters “Suhara; Majeed; Narayani”",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammed Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70749,
    "questionText": " Which fish was declared as ths;official fish of Kerala in 2010?",
    "answerText": " Etroplus (pearl spot)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70750,
    "questionText": " DOS (Disc Operating System) was developed by ?",
    "answerText": " Tim Patterson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70751,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Great Expectations?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70752,
    "questionText": " Theory of Population was propounded by ?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Malthus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70753,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Atoms of Hope”?",
    "answerText": " Mohan Sundar Rajan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70754,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Mothiram”?",
    "answerText": " Karoor Neelakanda Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70755,
    "questionText": " Lady Rattan Tata Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Hockey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70756,
    "questionText": " First Indian state to pass a Sports Bill is?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70757,
    "questionText": " Broadest Street (World)?",
    "answerText": " Broadway St. (USA)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70758,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Metamorphoses ?",
    "answerText": " Ovid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70759,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Inside CBI ?",
    "answerText": " Joginder Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70760,
    "questionText": " Herman Gundert lived and worked at?",
    "answerText": " Illikkunnu in Thalassery."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70761,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Razor (Safety)?",
    "answerText": " Gillette"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70762,
    "questionText": " Vitamin B4deficiency causes ?",
    "answerText": " Anemia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70763,
    "questionText": " Largest Desert in Asia?",
    "answerText": " Gobi (Mongolia)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70764,
    "questionText": " The Theory of Money and Credit was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Ludwig von Mises"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70765,
    "questionText": " Risk; Uncertainty; and Profit was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Frank H. Knight"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70766,
    "questionText": " Turpentine oil is obtained from?",
    "answerText": " Pinus tree."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70767,
    "questionText": " The animals feeding on blood are known as?",
    "answerText": " Sanguivores"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70768,
    "questionText": " Kerla's first Wind Farm is situated in?",
    "answerText": " Kanjikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70769,
    "questionText": " Headquarters of UNDP is at?",
    "answerText": " New York"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70770,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Singapore?",
    "answerText": " Singapore City"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70771,
    "questionText": " Highest Water fall (India)?",
    "answerText": " Gersoppa Waterfall (Karnataka)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70772,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Bachelor of Arts”?",
    "answerText": " R.K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70773,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Fiesta”?",
    "answerText": " Ernest Hemingway"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70774,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Yashodhara ?",
    "answerText": " Maithili Sharan Gupt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70775,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Agnisakshi “?",
    "answerText": " Lalitham bika Antharjenam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70776,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Ship (turbine)?",
    "answerText": " Charles Parsons"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70777,
    "questionText": " Most famous ruler of Mali in Africa is?",
    "answerText": " Manga Kangan Muza"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70778,
    "questionText": " Highest River Bridge?",
    "answerText": " Royal Gorge; 321 m above sea level on the river Arkansas; 268 m long; Colorado."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70779,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Mauritania?",
    "answerText": " Nouakchott"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70780,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Jai Somnath”?",
    "answerText": " K.M. Munshi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70781,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Communist Manifesto”?",
    "answerText": " Karl Marx and Friedrich"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70782,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Mayor of Caster Bridge”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70783,
    "questionText": " Tommy Emar Gold Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Hockey (Women)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70784,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Back to Methuselah ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70785,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Shishyanum Makanum”?",
    "answerText": " Vallathol Narayana Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70786,
    "questionText": " Kundara Proclamation was in ?",
    "answerText": 1809
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70787,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Utopia-A Bold New World”?",
    "answerText": " Shishir Gupta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70788,
    "questionText": " Pollination by wind is called?",
    "answerText": " Anemophily"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70789,
    "questionText": " Global Polio Eradication Programme is a Joint effort led by WHO; UNICEF and ?",
    "answerText": " The Rotory Foundation."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70790,
    "questionText": " In 1983;an American company Eli Lily; produced the first genetically engineered insulin. Name it?",
    "answerText": " Humulin (with the help of Escherichia Coli (or E-coli))"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70791,
    "questionText": " Heaviest Rain Fall (World)?",
    "answerText": " M a w s y n r a m (Meghalaya)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70792,
    "questionText": " First and the Last Indian Governor – General of Free India?",
    "answerText": " C. Rajagopalachari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70793,
    "questionText": " St. Peters Basilica in Rome was built under the patronage of Pope Julius II and Pope Leo X It was designed by?",
    "answerText": " Michelangelo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70794,
    "questionText": " Which was the first political novel?",
    "answerText": " Parappuram by Kurukkal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70795,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of On Government?",
    "answerText": " Edmund Burke"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70796,
    "questionText": " The organism which has the maximum number of ribs is?",
    "answerText": " Snake."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70797,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Electric Attraction?",
    "answerText": " Coulomb"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70798,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Summer in Calcutta?",
    "answerText": " Kamala Das"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70799,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Experiments with Untruth”?",
    "answerText": " Michael Anderson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70800,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Essays on Life”?",
    "answerText": " Samuel Butler"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70801,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Malawi?",
    "answerText": " Lilongwe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70802,
    "questionText": " 'C' programming language was developed by ?",
    "answerText": " Dennis Ritchie."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70803,
    "questionText": " Who was the president of America to devalue the dollar In August -1971 due to economic troubles and the cost of financing the Vietnam War?",
    "answerText": " Richard Nixon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70804,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Paraguay?",
    "answerText": " Guarani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70805,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Virginians; The”?",
    "answerText": " William Thackeray"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70806,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Gone with the Wind ?",
    "answerText": " Margaret Mitchell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70807,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Cell Theory?",
    "answerText": " Schleiden & Schwann"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70808,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mudra Rakshasa”?",
    "answerText": " Vishakhadatta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70809,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Manikan”?",
    "answerText": " Lalitham bika Antharjenam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70810,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Poliomyelitis (vaccine)?",
    "answerText": " Jonas Salk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70811,
    "questionText": " Largest Mammal in the world is ?",
    "answerText": " Blue Whales"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70812,
    "questionText": " Zinjanthropus; considered to be the earliest in the human species were found in the?",
    "answerText": " Great Rift Valley of Central Africa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70813,
    "questionText": " The Raja's court of appeal was reconstituted as the Chief Court of Cochin in?",
    "answerText": 1900
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70814,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters “Juliet; Miranda; Othello”",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70815,
    "questionText": " In which year Amartya Sen won the Nobel Prize for Welfare Economics?",
    "answerText": 1998
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70816,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Portugal?",
    "answerText": " Escudo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70817,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Golden Note Book ?",
    "answerText": " Doris Lessing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70818,
    "questionText": " When Kerala was formed on linguistic basics which of the Malayalam speaking Indian states were merged together?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70819,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Yesterday and Today ?",
    "answerText": " K.P.S. Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70820,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Fatal Cart; Reconciliation Why and How”?",
    "answerText": " C.Rajagopalachari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70821,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of What Went Wrong ?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70822,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Midsummer Night’s Dream”?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70823,
    "questionText": " The percentage of light energy fixed in photosynthesis is generally around ?",
    "answerText": 0.01
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70824,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Norway?",
    "answerText": " Kroner"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70825,
    "questionText": " First Prime Minister of India?",
    "answerText": " Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70826,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Servants of India”?",
    "answerText": " RK Laxman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70827,
    "questionText": " ……is the market for very short term loans?",
    "answerText": " Money Market"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70828,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Naked Face”?",
    "answerText": " Sydney Sheldon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70829,
    "questionText": " First Dalit Speaker of the Lok Sabha?",
    "answerText": " G.M.C. Balayoki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70830,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of T.N.T. (high explosive)?",
    "answerText": " Will Brand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70831,
    "questionText": " An account of a memorable experience is known as?",
    "answerText": " Reminiscence"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70832,
    "questionText": " The first passenger railway was opened from?",
    "answerText": " Liverpool to Manchester"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70833,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Atom-breaking up the nucleus?",
    "answerText": " Rutherford"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70834,
    "questionText": " Kerala Folklore Academy It is an autonomous Corporate body constituted on?",
    "answerText": " 28-Jun-95"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70835,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Don Quixote”?",
    "answerText": " Cervantes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70836,
    "questionText": " In which year Travancore Broadcasting station was merged with All India Radio Network?",
    "answerText": " 1st April 1950"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70837,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Years of Pilgrimage?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Raja Ramanna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70838,
    "questionText": " Name the first digital computer designed by Howard Alken?",
    "answerText": " 'Harvard Mark l"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70839,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Devadasi”?",
    "answerText": " Sugathakumari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70840,
    "questionText": " American President who is known as 'Black Horse’?",
    "answerText": " James K Polk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70841,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Communist Manifesto ?",
    "answerText": " Karl Marx"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70842,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Gurusagaram”?",
    "answerText": " O.V Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70843,
    "questionText": " Who was the First Malayali woman to participate in Olympics?",
    "answerText": " PT Usha (1980 Moscow Olympics)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70844,
    "questionText": " Land of Thunderbolt?",
    "answerText": " Bhutan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70845,
    "questionText": " Who was the last Chief Justice of Travaneore High Court?",
    "answerText": " Puthupally Krishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70846,
    "questionText": " First university in the world was started in ?",
    "answerText": " Paris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70847,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Good Earth ?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70848,
    "questionText": " French society on- the eve of Revolution was divided into three Estates; which are they?",
    "answerText": " Clergy; Nobles and Commons"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70849,
    "questionText": " The Human development Index can have a value between?",
    "answerText": " 0 and 1"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70850,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Changing”?",
    "answerText": " Liv Ullmaan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70851,
    "questionText": " First Bachelor President of America is?",
    "answerText": " James Buccanan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70852,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Beast and Man”?",
    "answerText": " Murry Midgley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70853,
    "questionText": " Hitler became the President of Germany in ?",
    "answerText": 1934
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70854,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Eritrea?",
    "answerText": " Asmara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70855,
    "questionText": " David Copperfield;",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70856,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Thottiyude Makan’?",
    "answerText": " Thakazhi Sivasankara Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70857,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Electric Battery?",
    "answerText": " Volta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70858,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Love in the time of Cholera ?",
    "answerText": " Gabriel Garcia Marquez"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70859,
    "questionText": " Vaikkom Satyagraha was in ?",
    "answerText": 1924
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70860,
    "questionText": " In the history of computer the fifth generation was started in ?",
    "answerText": 1980
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70861,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Zambia?",
    "answerText": " Kwacha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70862,
    "questionText": " Which is the only overland connection between China and Pakistan?",
    "answerText": " Karakkoram highway"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70863,
    "questionText": " which disease may be caused by Radiation ?",
    "answerText": " Leukaemia."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70864,
    "questionText": " Japan joined the Second World War in the year ?",
    "answerText": 1940
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70865,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Eureka”?",
    "answerText": " Edgar Allen Poe."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70866,
    "questionText": " The first network that planted the seeds of internet was?",
    "answerText": " ARPANET"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70867,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Old Man and the Sea?",
    "answerText": " Earnest Hemingway."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70868,
    "questionText": " Largest Temple?",
    "answerText": " Angkor Vat. 162.6 ha area; built for Lord Vishnu by Khmer King Suryavarman-II during 1113-50 A.D. (Cambodia)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70869,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Twelfth Night ?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70870,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Mozambique?",
    "answerText": " Metical"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70871,
    "questionText": " Tropical forests are also known as ?",
    "answerText": " Evergreen Rain forests."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70872,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of St Joan ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70873,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Zimbabwe?",
    "answerText": " Harare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70874,
    "questionText": " The birthplace of Malayalam poet P Kunjiraman Nair is in?",
    "answerText": " Kanjangadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70875,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Midnight's Children”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70876,
    "questionText": " A general decline in prices; often caused by a reduction in the supply of money or credit is called ?",
    "answerText": " Deflation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70877,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Safety Pin?",
    "answerText": " William Hunt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70878,
    "questionText": " 'The Prince”; a book on politics is written by?",
    "answerText": " Niccolo Machiavelli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70879,
    "questionText": " The tutelary diety of the city 'UR' in Mesopotamia ?",
    "answerText": " Nannar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70880,
    "questionText": " The first heart transplantation in Kerala was conducted at Cochin Medical Trust Hospital under the guidance of ?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Jose Chacko Periyapuram."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70881,
    "questionText": " Kim",
    "answerText": " Rudyard Kipling"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70882,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Being Digital?",
    "answerText": " Nicholas Ncgroponte"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70883,
    "questionText": " Which was the first professional football club in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " F C Cochin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70884,
    "questionText": " Which is Asia's largest naval academy?",
    "answerText": " Ezhimala Indian Naval Academy (Kannur)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70885,
    "questionText": " Stalingrad is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Volga"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70886,
    "questionText": " Don Quixote",
    "answerText": " Cerventes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70887,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Sigmond Freud belongs to which country”?",
    "answerText": " Austria"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70888,
    "questionText": " Which was a telecommunication link established since 1963 between the Kremlin (Moscow) and White House (Washington DC; USA) ?",
    "answerText": " HOTLINE"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70889,
    "questionText": " What is the total number of permanent teeth in an adult ?",
    "answerText": 32
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70890,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Lady of the Lake?",
    "answerText": " Sir Walter Scott"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70891,
    "questionText": " World Bank classifies the countries of the world into three; they are?",
    "answerText": " low income; middle income and high income countries"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70892,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Dharmaraja Nirupanam' ?",
    "answerText": " Swadeshabhimani Ramakrishnapilla."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70893,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Switzerland?",
    "answerText": " Berne"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70894,
    "questionText": " Botanical survey of India (BSI) with its head office in Kolkata came into existence in?",
    "answerText": 1890
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70895,
    "questionText": " The chief function of phloem is the conduction of…?",
    "answerText": " Food"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70896,
    "questionText": " In which battle Narmudicheral defeated Ay Ruler Nannan?",
    "answerText": " Vagai Peruthurai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70897,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ritu Samhara”?",
    "answerText": " Kalidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70898,
    "questionText": " The Roman Governor who gave the verdict to crucify Christ?",
    "answerText": " Pontheos Pelathose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70899,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Ganadevata?",
    "answerText": " Tara Shankar Bandopadyaya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70900,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Bolivian Diary?",
    "answerText": " Ernesto Che Guera"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70901,
    "questionText": " The place known as the Financial Capital of Europe is?",
    "answerText": " Zurich in Switzerland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70902,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Crisis into Chaos”?",
    "answerText": " E.M.S.Namboodiripad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70903,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Ecuador?",
    "answerText": " Quito"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70904,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Apple is?",
    "answerText": " Malus Sylvestris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70905,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kumara Sambhava”?",
    "answerText": " Kalidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70906,
    "questionText": " College of Military Engineering is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kirkee; Pune (Maharashtra)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70907,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Julius Caesar”?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70908,
    "questionText": " Flightless Bird?",
    "answerText": " Swift"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70909,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tirayum Chuzhiyum “?",
    "answerText": " Prof. S. Guptan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70910,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Poland?",
    "answerText": " Zloty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70911,
    "questionText": " Most famous Paleolithic man was the Neandarthal Man was discovered from ?",
    "answerText": " Germany"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70912,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ascent to Everest”?",
    "answerText": " Sir John Hunt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70913,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Ramanujan?",
    "answerText": " Indira Parthasarathy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70914,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Coolies”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70915,
    "questionText": " are based on the principle that the rate of water absorption is essentially equal to the rate of water loss?",
    "answerText": " Potometers"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70916,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Disc Brake?",
    "answerText": " Lanchester"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70917,
    "questionText": " The tomb of the king Pazhassi Raja is in?",
    "answerText": " Mananthavady"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70918,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Airship?",
    "answerText": " Giffard"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70919,
    "questionText": " The American Model Executive was proposed by?",
    "answerText": " Sir C. P. Ramaswami Ayyer."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70920,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Farewell to Trumpets”?",
    "answerText": " James Morris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70921,
    "questionText": " What was the real name of Chatampi Swamikal?",
    "answerText": " Kunjan Pillai."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70922,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Indian Homerule”?",
    "answerText": " Gandhiji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70923,
    "questionText": " Pope John Paul II died on?",
    "answerText": " 2nd April 2005"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70924,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tharavadu and Oru Muri Tenga”?",
    "answerText": " P. Kesava Dev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70925,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Salk Vaccine (Anti Polio)?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Jonas E.Salk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70926,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Nehru The Making of India”?",
    "answerText": " MJ. Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70927,
    "questionText": " Whis is the Largest leaf?",
    "answerText": " Victoria regia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70928,
    "questionText": " Yachana Yathra led by V.T. Bhattathirippadu in 1931 was from?",
    "answerText": " Trichur to Chandragiri river."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70929,
    "questionText": " Iravikulam National Park, established in 1978 is in?",
    "answerText": " Idukki district"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70930,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Fathers and Sons?",
    "answerText": " Ivan Turgenev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70931,
    "questionText": " Who formed a society of monks known as 'Jesut order' in Spain ?",
    "answerText": " Ignatius Layola"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70932,
    "questionText": " Who were the able lieutenants of Pazhassi ?",
    "answerText": " Kannavath Sankaran Nambiar;Kaiteri Ambu Nair; Edachanna Kungan Nair and"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70933,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Faces of Everest ?",
    "answerText": " Maj H P SAhluwalia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70934,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Waiting for the Mahatma. “?",
    "answerText": " R.K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70935,
    "questionText": " Sultan Bateri's earlier name was?",
    "answerText": " Ganapathivattam."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70936,
    "questionText": " Perikalan Andhru",
    "answerText": " S.K. Pottakadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70937,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Tom Jones?",
    "answerText": " Henry Fielding"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70938,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Search for Home; ”?",
    "answerText": " A Sashti Brata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70939,
    "questionText": " First man who climbed Mount Everest (twice)?",
    "answerText": " Nawang Gombu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70940,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Arms and the Man”?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70941,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Jungle Girl”?",
    "answerText": " Ginu Karnani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70942,
    "questionText": " Lepracy causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Myco bacterium Leprae"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70943,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of India Divided ?",
    "answerText": " Rajendra Prasad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70944,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Nuclear Physics?",
    "answerText": " John Crockfort"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70945,
    "questionText": " National Socialist German Workers Party founded in 1920was known as ?",
    "answerText": " Nazi Party"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70946,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Essays of”?",
    "answerText": " Elia Charles Lamb"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70947,
    "questionText": " Development as Freedom was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70948,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Don Quixote”",
    "answerText": " Cerventes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70949,
    "questionText": " In which year Vasco Da Gama returned to Lisbon?",
    "answerText": 1499
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70950,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Gita Rahasya”?",
    "answerText": " Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70951,
    "questionText": " American Airlines Flight 11 and United Airlines Flight 175 were crashed into the Twin Towers of the World Trade Center in New York City by the hijackers on ?",
    "answerText": " 11-Sep-01"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70952,
    "questionText": " The first film which uses the morphing ?",
    "answerText": " WllLOW"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70953,
    "questionText": " Name the first E-governance programme launched in Andhra Pradesh?",
    "answerText": " E-sewa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70954,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Somalia?",
    "answerText": " Somali Shilling"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70955,
    "questionText": " The Britain passed The Town Shend Act in American colonies in ?",
    "answerText": 1767
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70956,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Democracy Redeemed”?",
    "answerText": " V.K.Narasimhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70957,
    "questionText": " Water Sports Centre of the Sports Authority of India is on?",
    "answerText": " The Punnamada Lake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70958,
    "questionText": " Which city is called by its natives as 'The Big Apple'?",
    "answerText": " NewYork"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70959,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Rehasyam”?",
    "answerText": " Karoor Neelakanda Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70960,
    "questionText": " Fats are richly found in ?",
    "answerText": " Adipose tissue"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70961,
    "questionText": " Which is the first cement factory in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Natakom Travancore Cements (Kottayam)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70962,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Crystal Dynamics?",
    "answerText": " C.V.Raman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70963,
    "questionText": " Prince of Wales Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Golf (England)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70964,
    "questionText": " Which organ of the body is affected by Typhoid?",
    "answerText": " Intestine; whole body"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70965,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Duchess of Malfi”?",
    "answerText": " John Webster"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70966,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kavya Narthaki”?",
    "answerText": " Changampuzha Krishna Pilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70967,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Dr. Faust?",
    "answerText": " Goethe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70968,
    "questionText": " Which organ of the body is affected by Jaundice ?",
    "answerText": " Liver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70969,
    "questionText": " The scheme of Travancore Devaswam Board to plant trees on barren temple premises is called?",
    "answerText": " Devaranyam scheme"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70970,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of A Hindu View of Life?",
    "answerText": " Dr. S.Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70971,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Three Sisters”?",
    "answerText": " Anton Chekov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70972,
    "questionText": " High income countries are known as?",
    "answerText": " Developed Countries"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70973,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the 'Father of DNA Finger Printing ?",
    "answerText": " Sir Alec Jeffreys"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70974,
    "questionText": " Robert Walpole became the Prime Minister of England in?",
    "answerText": 1721
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70975,
    "questionText": " Which element helps in flowering of plants?",
    "answerText": " Phosphorous"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70976,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “A Billion is Enough”?",
    "answerText": " Ashok Gupta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70977,
    "questionText": " Sickman of Europe?",
    "answerText": " Turkey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70978,
    "questionText": " Which gland secretes tears in the eyes?",
    "answerText": " Lachrymal gland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70979,
    "questionText": " Oval (England) is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70980,
    "questionText": " Chalcolithic Period is also known as ?",
    "answerText": " Metal Age"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70981,
    "questionText": " The Monastry of Monte Casino was founded by?",
    "answerText": " St. Benedict"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70982,
    "questionText": " Kuppuswamy Naidu Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Hockey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70983,
    "questionText": " Largest Sea-bird?",
    "answerText": " Albatross"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70984,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Area of Darkness”?",
    "answerText": " V.S.Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70985,
    "questionText": " Indian Institute of Petroleum is located at?",
    "answerText": " Dehra Dun (Uttar Pradesh)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70986,
    "questionText": " The first Women Police Station started functioning in Kozhikode on?",
    "answerText": " 27-Oct-73"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70987,
    "questionText": " IBAN expands to?",
    "answerText": " International Bank Account Number"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70988,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Atomic Numbers?",
    "answerText": " Moseley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70989,
    "questionText": " ................is a blood circulation problem; resulting from accumulation of fatty deposits in the walls of the blood vessels; especially arteries?",
    "answerText": " Atherosclerosis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70990,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Yayati ?",
    "answerText": " V.S. Khandekar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70991,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Turkey?",
    "answerText": " Turkish Lira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70992,
    "questionText": " Measles vaccine was discovered by ?",
    "answerText": " John F. Enders (1960)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70993,
    "questionText": " Charles I; the ruler of England; was beheaded publically in the year?",
    "answerText": 1649
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70994,
    "questionText": " Which is the birthplace of the great Mappila poet Moyinkutty Vaidyar?",
    "answerText": " Kondotty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70995,
    "questionText": " An excessive comedy writing is called?",
    "answerText": " Farce"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70996,
    "questionText": " The first page that you normally view at a Web site is its ?",
    "answerText": " Home page"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70997,
    "questionText": " Zorastrianism (Persian religion) was founded by ?",
    "answerText": " Zorathushtrar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70998,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Poverty and Famine”?",
    "answerText": " Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 70999,
    "questionText": " Largest Delta?",
    "answerText": " (Sunderbans). The World's largest delta is that created by the Ganges and Brahma putra in Bangladesh and West Bengal; India. It covers an area of 30; 000 sq. miles."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71000,
    "questionText": " Which Chief Minister of Kerala ruled for the longest term?",
    "answerText": " E.K. Nayanar"
  }
]